Guide to the Marie P. Tarnapowicz Papers, 1923-1980 AIS.1980.21
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Marie P. Tarnapowicz Papers
1923-1980
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Tarnapowicz, Marie
AIS.1980.21
22.5 Linear Feet
The Papers of Marie P. Tarnapowicz contain testimonials, a certificate, letters of commendations, photographs, and posters regarding her involvement in selling United States War Bonds during and immediately after World War II.
Biography
Not much is known about Marie P. Tarnapowicz, other than her participation and leadership in the selling of war bonds during and following World War II. The materials in this collection provide evidence of Mrs. Tarnapowicz's devotion to the cause and how she was recognized for her work.
Scope and Content Notes
The Papers of Marie P. Tarnapowicz consist of testimonials, a certificate, letters of commendations, photographs, and posters regarding her involvement in selling United States War Bonds during and immediately after World War II. Many women all over the United States, including Mrs. Tarnapowicz, sold war bonds as part of a women's campaign to contribute in the war. All the materials in this collection directly concern Mrs. Tarnapowicz's participation in selling war bonds.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marie P. Tarnapowicz in 1980.
Previous Citation
Marie P. Tarnapowicz Papers, 1923-1980, AIS.1980.21, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Women; Personal papers; United States -- History -- 1933-1945; Pennsylvania -- History; Savings bonds -- United States -- History; World War, 1939-1945 -- Women -- Pennsylvania; World War, 1939-1945 -- Social aspects -- Pennsylvania; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Pennsylvania; Tarnapowicz, Marie
- Photograph of streetcars painted red, white and blue (Map-case 7, Drawer 2)
- Correspondence, from Vernon L. Clark, National Director of the U.S. Savings Bond Division, Januay 15, 1947
- U.S. Treasury check, n.d.
- Photographs, ground breaking ceremony of Pittsburgh Veterans Hospital
- Reproduction of speech given by George Washington, n.d.
- Letter of commendation from Mayor Cornelius D. Scully, November 11, 1945
- Photograph of booth where bonds were sold in downtown Pittsburgh
- Photograph of Tarnapowicz presenting award to nationality workers, n.d.
- Certificate of participation, n.d.
- News release and photograph of War Bond Rally
- 2 photographs of christening of Father Francis A. Betha Liberty Ship, January 20, 1945
- Petition to Pittsburgh Railways Co., n.d.
- "Mrs. Francis P. Tarnapowicz -- A Great American", n.d.
- Poster for war bond drive for veterens hospitals
- Testimony to Tarnapowicz from Nationality Group, n.d.
- Resolution from Allegheny County, PA honoring Tarnapowicz, April 19, 1923
- Resolution from Allegheny County, PA, August 4, 1980
- Poster, war bonds